贝克特
Beckett?
我特意
I have delicately placed
在一块超级完美融化的巧克力上
one graham cracker, exactly six marshmallows,
放了一块全麦饼干  六块果浆软糖
at top a perfectly melted chocolate bar.
亲爱的  煎蛋饼里放这些  不会吧
In an omelet, darling, really?
这可不是煎蛋饼
Not an omelet.
-这是糖心蛋饼  -随你吧
- A s'morelet. - Uh-huh.
-来一块吧  -不  谢了
- Care for one? - No, thank you.
你呢  宝贝
What about you, sweetheart?
准备好在美味的早餐中来感受
Are you ready for your taste buds to be launched
-味觉天堂了吗  -当然  谢谢
- into breakfast nirvana? - Sure, thanks.
奥  今天晚上
Oh, is it okay
我的朋友阿什利要来可以吗
if my friend Ashley comes over tonight?
行  没问题  吃吧
Yes, of course. Now eat.
老爸
Dad.
-这里面放了棉花糖  -对
- Are there marshmallows in this? - Yes.
-还放了巧克力  -没错
- And chocolate? - Yes.
这才是精华所在啊
That's the point.
这是块糖心蛋饼
It's a s'morelet.
我得走了  爱你
I... I gotta go. Love you.
-爱你  -回见  亲爱的
- Love you. - Bye, honey.
恩
Mmm.
这简直赶上我的
This is almost as good as my
油煎巧克力慕斯面卷饼了
chocolate mousse chimichanga.
我就知道你会喜欢的
Aha. I knew you'd reconsider.
大卫·哈塞尔霍夫
"海滩救护队"主演
就像大卫·哈塞尔霍夫
it's kinda like David Hasselhoff.
开始你很反感  但是之后很奇怪的
At first you're repulsed, but then strangely,
你就喜欢上了
you're drawn in.
啊不  现在依然反感  回见
No, still repulsed. Bye.
真不知道阿丽克西斯是怎么了
Wonder what's up with Alexis?
她看上去有点心不在焉的
She seems a little out of it.
多明显啊
Isn't it obvious?
-怎么了  -她恋爱了
- What? - Oh, she's in love.
-阿丽克西斯吗  -当然了  亲爱的
- Alexis? - Oh, come on, darling.
你不会还没意识到吧
In case you haven't noticed,
她已经不是个小女孩儿了
she's not a little girl anymore.
谢谢您提醒了  老妈
Thank you, mother.
我觉得阿丽克西斯要是恋爱了
I think if Alexis were in love,
-肯定会告诉我的  -那可不一定
- she would've told me. - Ah, ah, ah, ah.
她没告诉你就证明她恋爱了
The fact that she hasn't told you is how we know it's real.
老妈
Mother.
其实昨天晚上她已经告诉我了
Okay, and the fact that she... mentioned it to me last night.
这个男孩子是谁  在哪认识的
Who is he? W-where did she meet him?
我不知道  她不肯说
I don't know. She wouldn't say.
我发誓  她什么也没告诉我
No, diva's honor. She didn't tell me anything.
连名字也没说
She didn't even tell me his name.
真不敢相信她连你都告诉了却没告诉我
I can't believe she told you and not me.
我才应该是她的"倾诉伙伴"
I'm supposed to be her go-to guy.
亲爱的  你当然是
Oh, darling, of course you are.
但是  你知道的  这是初恋
It's just, you know, it's first love.
很神奇  很难以捉摸
It's magical, ethereal.
不能以常理来判断的
It defies logic.
理查德  你电话
Richard, your phone?
恩
Mm.
奥  是贝克特
Oh, Beckett.
可能又有迷离谋杀案了  亲爱的
Maybe it's a nice murder, darling.
你今天又有事情可做了
Brighten your day.
好孩子
Good boy.
卡塞尔
Castle.
阿丽克西斯刚开始学走路的时候
When Alexis took her first steps,
我扶着她怕她摔倒
I was there to catch her when she fell.
她第一次学骑没有练习轮子的自行车
The first time she rode her bike without training wheels,
也是我像疯子似的
I was the maniac
在后面跟着她在大街上跑
chasing her down the street
大喊着让她不要撞到
screaming for her to watch out
拄拐棍的老太太
for the old lady with the walker.
甚至她刚学会说话的时候
Even her first word--
我猜猜  学会的是叫爸爸
Let me guess. "Daddy"?
-不是  是"结局"  -奥
- No, it was "Denouement." - Oh.
从幼儿抓起  我就给她强调
I stressed story structure
-故事结构的重要性  -是吗
- from an early age. - Uh-huh.
不管怎么说  我担心以后
Anyway, I'm afraid that
我们之间的那种特殊的情感
this is the beginning of the end
会就此消失了
of our special thing.
你知道吗  我可不担心  卡塞尔
Well, you know, I wouldn't worry, Castle.
我看到过她看你的那种眼神
I mean, I've seen the way that she looks at you.
你的真正问题是
Your real problem is
特别崇拜自己父亲的女孩子
that girls who adore their daddies
通常会嫁个一个和自己父亲很像的人
usually end up marrying guys just like them.
-是吗  -帕里什医生
- They do? - Dr. Parish.
早  辨别身份了吗
Good morning. Got an I.D.?
还没  怎么你们从来就不知道
Not yet. How come you guys
给我带杯咖啡呢
never bring me coffee?
你们还没来我就开始干活了
I'm here before you doing all the work.
我这还有剩下的
You can have the rest of mine.
其实  我不喝咖啡
Actually, I don't drink coffee.
可是给我带块熊掌糕能要你命啊
But would it kill you to bring me a bear claw?
说到要命
Speaking of killing.
胸部中一枪
Single G.S.W. to the chest,
大枪口径  大约45毫米
large caliber, probably a .45.
尸斑显示死亡时间大概是半夜
Lividity suggests time of death around midnight.
嘿
Hey.
我也有条那样的拳击短裤
I have those boxers.
托马斯·纳什的
Thomas Nash.
英国非常贵的一个牌子
Very pricey British brand.
非常的柔软  是丝绸的
Amazingly soft. They're silk.
我只是说  他被打死的时候
I'm just saying, he was probably very comfortable
应该挺舒服的
when he was shot and killed.
深更半夜的他几乎裸着
So what was this guy doing out here
在这儿是做什么呢
practically naked at midnight?
卡塞尔  少提你那些谬论了
Don't bother with any of your perverted theories, Castle.
我在伤口弹孔里找到了衣物纤维
I found fibers in the bullet hole.
也就是说他死时
Which means he was wearing clothes
-是穿着衣服的  -这说不通啊
- when he was shot. - That doesn't make any sense.
凶手杀了人
The killer shot him
又把血淋淋得衣服脱下来
and then hung around to take his bloody clothes off him?
可能凶手是担心衣服上会留下
Well, maybe the killer was worried that there was
暴露自己和死者关系的法医证据
forensic evidence on the clothes that would connect them.
警员在第五大街附近的垃圾桶里
Yo. Uni found this wallet
找到了这个钱包
out in a garbage can near fifth.
证件照片和这位内裤超人是一个人
Photo on the license matches Captain Underpants here.
不好意思  我小侄子很喜欢看那些书
Sorry. My nephew loves those books.
丹尼尔·戈尔茨坦  25岁
Daniel Goldstein, 25,
住在苏豪区
lives in soho.
他在伯曼罗斯上班
Yeah, he's also got a work I.D. from Berman Rose
在华尔街
down on wall street.
那就是说他在市区住  在市区上班
So he lived downtown and he worked downtown.
那他来这里做什么呢
What was he doing way up here?
把这带回实验室
Let's take this down to the lab.
好的
Right.
我穿拳击短裤
So I wear boxers.
那你穿什么呢
What do you wear--
丁字裤  性感小裤裤
thongs, Cheekies?
我都把自己的告诉你了
I told you mine.
灯笼裤
Bloomers?
还是美少女大花裤衩
Granny panties?
难道你不穿内裤
Commando?
他衣服被拿走了
His clothes were taken?
怎么会有人拿他衣服呢
Why would anyone take his clothes?
我们不清楚戈尔茨坦小姐
We don't know, Ms. Goldstein.
能告诉我们
Can you tell us what your brother
你哥哥去公园可能会干什么
might have been doing in the park?
那么晚了  我不知道
That late? I have no idea.
发现丹尼尔尸体的地方
Well, the place where Daniel was found
经常进行毒品交易  他在吸毒吗
is known for drug activity. Was he using?
没有  他连酒都不怎么喝
No. He barely even drank.
你知道他最近有和什么人结仇
Did he have any enemies
或者闹矛盾吗
or conflicts that you know of?
不  没有  听着  这些都说不过去
No, no. Look, none of this makes any sense.
这  这根本不是他的作为
It's just-- it's not like him.
我们父母因一场车祸都去世了
Our parents both died in a car accident
那时他十二岁
when he was 12,
从那时起他就非常谨慎
and since then, he's always been so cautious.
他有女朋友吗
What about dating?
有没有什么特殊的人
Was there anyone special in his life?
他倒想呢  但是没有
Oh, he wished, but no.
他很少有社交活动  不怎么和人打交道
No, he barely had a social life or social skills.
我是说  他太善良了
I mean, he was such a sweetheart,
但是善良的像个呆子
but a dork, you know?
况且他总是在上班
And he was always at work anyway.
在伯曼罗斯吗
At Berman Rose?
他做什么工作
What did he do for them?
做金融产品
Created financial products.
他简直是个数学天才
He was this incredible math genius.
在麻省理工拿到了博士
Got his PHD from M.I.T.
我以为他肯定会当个教授或者什么的
I thought for sure he'd be a professor or something,
但是这些对冲基金公司
but these hedge funds,
他们就需要这种人才
they hire guys like him,
酬劳非常高
and they pay them obscene amounts of money.
他刚25岁就给我买了套房子
25 years old--he bought my apartment for me.
不好意思
Excuse me.
什么情况
What's up?
实验室在死者钱包上获取一枚指纹
Lab got a fingerprint off our vic's wallet.
是不是个善茬
Anyone good?
这个...
Uh...
过去一个月
Awaiting court dates
因为三次严重伤人罪
on three aggravated assault cases
准备上庭受审  唐瑞德先生
in the past month, Mr. D'andrad.
你打断过N个人的肋骨
You inflicted dozens of broken bones,
把其中一个人眼睛挖了出来
gouged out one of your victim's eyes,
还咬掉过别人的耳朵
bit off part of an ear of another one.
看起来你这种人不犯罪才不正常呢
Sounds like committing murder was inevitable.
我只是很好奇
I'm just curious.
你为什么要拿走死者的衣服
Why did you take his clothes?
不是我拿的
Wasn't me.
那为什么死者的钱包上
Well, then why were your fingerprints
有你的指纹
on a dead man's wallet?
别告诉我他刚好掉了钱包
Did he just happen to drop it,
你就好心的捡起来还给了他
and you politely picked it up for him?
为什么我的手下在你的住所
And why did my detectives find
找到了这把45口径的没注册的手枪
this unregistered 45 in your apartment,
这把手枪又这么巧
which just happens to match
和死者伤口的枪口直径大小一致
the size of the bullet hole in my victim?
-嘿  -你要是清白的
- Hey. - If you're so innocent,
唐瑞德先生
Mr. D'andrad,
你为什么拒捕
why did you resist arrest
还把我一个手下的头往墙上撞
and try to put one of my detectives through a wall?
兄弟  你知道  穿个合适的高领绒衣
You know, the right turtleneck,
别人也看不出来
and no one is even gonna notice, bro.
或者围条围巾
Maybe a scarf.
你干脆说实话吧
Why don't you just confess to the truth?
反正迟早你也要招供的
It's gonna come out sooner or later.
我看见的时候他已经死了
He was already dead.
钱包就那么碰巧放在他的旁边吗
With a wallet lying conveniently next to him?
听着  如果你不想承认你的罪行
Uh, look, if you're not going to admit to it,
至少也要编个像样点的故事
you might at least want to try coming up with a story
-出来啊  -我说的是实话
- that's a little more convincing. - It's what happened!
难道你没害怕吗
Like you weren't scared.
这家伙应该关起来  贝克特
I want this guy to fry, Beckett.
他会的
Oh, he will,
只要蕾妮能确定子弹口径是点45
as soon as Lanie confirms that that bullet is a .45.
-不是点45  -你确定吗
- It's not a .45. - Are you sure?
-很确定  -点38
- I'm positive. - .38?
不是  也不是点44或是点357
Nope. It's not a .44 or a .357
也不是点22或是9毫米口径
or a .22 or a 9 millimeter
是一种我根本就没见过的子弹
or any other kind of bullet I've ever seen.
这么说就是一种新型子弹咯
So it's a new kind of bullet.
不是  一点都不新  看看吧
Oh, no. Not new at all. Check it out.
- 是圆形子弹  - 你看到那种白色的外壳了吗
- Oh, it's round. - You see that white coating?
看见了  那是什么  氧化物吗
Yeah. What is it, oxidation?
- 准确的说是氧化铅  -锈吗
- Lead oxide, to be exact. - Rust?
是的  根据氧化铅的含量
Yep. Based on the amount of it,
我判断那子弹有200年的历史
I'd say that bullet is 200 years old.
一颗有200年历史子弹只可能意味着一件事
A 200-year-old bullet can only mean one thing.
一位时间旅行的凶手
Time-traveling killer.
因此  凶手可能是通过时间涟漪
Ergo, the killer could've entered present time
来到我们这个时代  杀掉古德斯坦
through a time ripple, killed Goldstein,
再通过时间涟漪返回
and then gone back through the time ripple,
也就是说我们要找到那个时间涟漪
which means we just have to find the time ripple.
求你别再提"时间涟漪"了
Could you please stop saying "Time ripple"?
好吧  听起来有点下流  是不是
Yeah. It sounds kinda dirty, doesn't it?
要是那个时间涟漪关闭了呢
What if the ripple closed?
时间机器
Time machine.
-我们需要一座时间机器  -当下
- We need a time machine. - Well, in this century,
我们还没有排除大块头唐瑞德的嫌疑
we still haven't ruled out our big buddy Mr. D'andrad.
是啊  不过他看起来不像是会时间旅行那种人
Yeah, he just doesn't seem like the time-travel type to me.
凶手一定不是时间旅行者
Can't be a time-traveling killer.
那子弹有200年的历史呢
Bullet had 200 years of rust on it.
如果凶手是时间旅行者
If the killer had been a time traveler,
子弹应该是新的
the bullet would've been brand-new.
除非时间旅行也能造成生锈
Unless time travel causes rust.
我看你是脑袋生锈了  你询问
On your brain. Have you followed up
死者的姐姐有关古董子弹的事情了吗
with the victim's sister regarding the antique bullet?
问了  她不知道古董子弹和古董枪的事
Yep. She has no clue about antique bullets or guns,
但是有人对那些很了解
But there's somebody who does.
阿贝·桑维奇  你要找的古董武器专家
Abe Sandrich--antique weapons expert you requested.
这名字让我感觉很饿
That reminds me, I'm starving.
我喜欢点45
I like .45s.
找到好的角度
Catch the right angle,
这家伙能把你的脑袋轰下来
this sucker could take your head clean off.
但是
But...
这把不是你要找的枪
It's not the gun you're looking for.
-为什么  -枪管必须重新组装
- Why is that? - Barrel would've had to be modified.
这把还跟出厂时一模一样
This one's factory fresh.
你觉得"巨人"唐瑞德说他在草地上
Well, do you think D'andrad the giant was telling the truth
找到钱包  说的是真话吗
when he said he found the wallet in the grass?
凶手的确是拿走了古德斯坦的衣服
Well, the killer did take Goldstein's clothes,
所以说在凶手离开犯罪现场的时候
so it's possible that the wallet might have fallen out
钱包有可能掉出来了
when he left the crime scene.
什么样的武器能发射这种子弹
What kind of a pistol would've fired that bullet?
通常我们管这个叫铅弹  原因显而易见
We usually just call 'em lead balls for, uh, obvious reasons.
很多18世纪的燧发枪都可以发射这种子弹
I'd say a whole lot of 18th century flintlocks--
但是枪种过多  无从推测
too many brands to even speculate.
你要找到那把枪
You'll need to find the actual pistol
才能有办法和这枚铅弹比对
to match it this lead ball.
有多少人
And how many people
有这种类型的古董枪呢
would own that kind of antique pistol?
很难讲
It's hard to say.
它们都被当做是收藏品
They're considered collectibles,
所以也就不用注册
so they don't have to be registered.
用它来杀人是聪明的选择
Making it pretty smart to kill someone with one.
那是当然  枪的年头可能有些久
Oh, yeah. The guns may be old,
但是其杀意可是丝毫不减
but, uh, they got plenty of killing left in 'em.
唐瑞德是凶手吗
So is, uh, D'andrad our guy?
-不是  -那他干嘛非要拒捕  害我受伤
- I'm afraid not. - W-why did he go all Hulk Hogan on me?
蝎子为什么要刺青蛙呢  那是他的本性
Well, why did the scorpion sting the frog? It's his nature.
唐瑞德只能在监狱
Yeah, well, D'andrad will be seeing nature
当蝎子了  他可是袭警了
from behind bars from now on for assaulting an officer.
我会争取给他上限惩罚的  警探
I'll see he gets the max, detective.
谢谢  队长
Thank you, Captain.
你可以休几天假的
You can take a couple days if you like,
-看点电影  -读读《赤裸热浪》
- catch some movies. - Read "Naked Heat."
不  不用了  长官
No. No need, sir.
还是没找到死者衣服
Still no luck with the clothes.
警队搜寻了公园以外
Units looked in every garbage can
5个街区范围内的垃圾桶
within 5-block radius of the park.
到底因为什么  凶手非要拿走
What is so special about these clothes
死者的衣服呢
that our killer would take them?
也许凶手时间旅行来了之后  是光着身子的
Maybe the killer came through the time ripple naked
需要死者的衣服
and needed the clothes...
就跟《终结者》情节一样
Like in "The Terminator."
很遗憾  目前我也没什么更好的推断
Sadly, I don't have a better theory at this point.
问题在于
So the question is,
一个像古德斯坦这样的华尔街数据处理员
What did a wall street number cruncher like Goldstein
到底惹上了什么麻烦
get himself into?
我和卡塞尔去他的公司调查一下
Castle and I will go to his firm.
你们查查相关社会媒体
You guys see if you can track down
和当地俱乐部
any antique gun enthusiasts
能不能找到古董枪的线索
on social media sites or local clubs.
也许能找到和古德斯坦生活有交集的人
Maybe someone from Goldstein's life will pop.
好的
You got it.
我就是想不通
You know, I just don't get
为什么凶手会射杀古德斯坦  偷他的衣服
how someone could shoot Goldstein, steal his clothes,
却偏偏留下了他的钱包
and then not hang on to his wallet.
不符合常理啊
It just doesn't make any sense.
是啊
No.
也许是巨蛾杀了他  把他的衣服吃掉了
Maybe giant moths killed him and then ate his clothes.
有可能
Could be.
卡塞尔
Hey, Castle.
如果这个案子你不感兴趣
If this case is boring for you,
你可以回家玩去
you don't have to stay.
没有  我在看我的邮箱
No, I-I'm just checking
短信  看看阿丽克西斯有没有打给我
my e-mails, my texts, see if Alexis called.
我不敢相信她竟然告诉我妈说她恋爱了
I can't believe she told my mother she's in love
-却没告诉我  -这样啊
- and is holding out on me. - Oh.
-我打给她  -别  你要等她告诉你
- I'm gonna call her. - No, no. You have to let her tell you
给她时间  等她准备好
in her own time, when she's ready.
我是超酷老爸  她还要准备什么
I'm the cool dad. Why can't she be ready?
听我说
Listen to me.
我小时候  我老爸也是这么干的
My dad tried to do the same thing when I was her age,
结果我和车库摇滚歌手约会了7个月
and I ended up dating a grunge rocker who smelled like
他身上的味道就像湿的法兰绒和丁香香烟
wet flannel and clove cigarettes for seven months.
你可不要招惹青春期的少女
You do not mess with a teenage girl and her hormones.
你说得对
You're right.
我不会给她打电话的
I won't call her.
-你刚刚说巨蛾了是吗  -没有
- Did you say something about a giant moth? - Nope.
穿着内裤被发现了
In his underwear?
丹尼为我工作两年了
Danny is working for me for two years.
我不知道他去公园干什么
But I just don't know what he'd have been up to in the park.
他不是那种喜欢户外运动的人
He wasn't exactly the outdoors type.
那古董枪呢  墨菲先生
What about antique guns, Mr. Murphy?
你知道这方面的事情吗
Do you know anything about them?
古董  不不  他也不喜欢枪什么的
Antiques? No. No, he wasn't into guns at all.
据我了解  他很晚下班
Well, I understand that he worked long hours.
昨晚他什么时候离开的
Do you know when he left last night?
大概在晚上九点半
Uh, yeah, right around 9:30.
让我来帮帮你
Oh, hey. Let me help you with that.
-谢谢  -这位是茱莉亚·福斯特  丹尼的助手
Thanks. This is Julia Foster, Danny's assistant.
这两位是贝克特探长和理查德·卡塞尔
This is Detective Beckett and Richard Castle.
-你好  -你好
- Hi. - Hi.
古德斯坦昨晚离开的时候你也在场啊
Were you here last night when Goldstein left?
-当然  -知道他去哪了吗
- Of course. - Any idea where he was heading?
不知道  他只是道了晚安
No, he just said good night.
白天的时候呢
And what about during the day,
有什么反常的行为吗
was there anything out of the ordinary,
或是奇怪的电话吗
any strange phone calls?
没有  不过是那些愤怒的投资者  不过
No, just the usual unhappy investor. Although...
不过什么
Although what?
低潮基金
The lower tide fund.
那是什么
What's that?
那是丹尼尔为我们创造的一种金融产品
It was one of the financial products Daniel created for us.
一种合成债务抵押债券
A synthetic C.D.O. cubed.
通俗点
English?
就是一种冒险
A really big bet that
汇率能够回到原来的样子
prices would return to historical norms.
-然后呢  -汇率又降了
- So what happened? - It tanked.
上千万美元一夜之间就没了
Hundreds of millions of dollars were lost overnight.
-什么时候的事  -三个月前
- When was this? - Three months ago.
有很多气愤的投资者
There must have been a lot of angry investors.
我们接到了
We fielded scores
客户几份比较"生动"的语音留言
of less-than-complimentary messages from clients.
简直是气得脸红脖子粗
More like apoplectic,
他们都埋怨丹尼
and a lot of them blamed Danny.
好吧  我们需要语音留言的副本
All right, well, I'll need a copy of all of these messages
和在基金中赔钱的客户名单
and a list of anyone who lost their money in the fund.
警探们  古董枪拥有者
Any luck connecting antique gun owners
和古德斯坦赔钱的基金客户有交集吗
to investors in Goldstein's failed fund, detectives?
没有  目前为止就在社区媒体网站上
Nah. So far I've seen a lot of cool, old guns
看到一些古董枪收藏者的很酷的古董枪
on these social media sites for antique gun lovers,
但是没人和古德斯坦有关联
But none of the owners pop in Goldstein's life.
快枪手厄文·芬克斯坦
Irwin "Quick draw" Finkelstein,
制造于1875年的雷明顿"恶徒"的拥有者
Proud owner of a Remington Outlaw made in 1875.
这枪可真漂亮
Now that's a great-looking gun.
看看  埃斯波西托
Check it out, Esposito.
是啊  真不错
Yeah, that's nice.
那个时候  枪更讲究其艺术性
See, back then, they were into the artistry of it all.
是啊  看起来就像是能杀人的雕塑
Yeah, they're like little sculptures that can kill.
名单上的投资者
Well, this list of lower tide fund investors,
他们很多人都赔了一百万
they all lost more than a million bucks apiece.
一百万
$1 million?
如果我有那么多钱
If I had that kind of scratch,
我会找个安全点的地方藏起来
I'd put it in something safe,
-比如说我的床垫里  -看看这个
- like my mattress. - Check it out.
山姆大叔  伊万·普多斯基
Ivan "Yosemite Sam" Podofski.
等等  伊万·普多斯基
Wait a minute. Ivan Podofski?
是啊  你有线索吗
Yeah, what do you got?
找到了
Boom.
看来找到赢家了
Looks like we have a winner.
说的对  他真挺像山姆大叔的
You're right. He does kinda look like Yosemite Sam.
头发不太像
On a bad hair day.
除了这把古董枪收藏
Yeah, well, in addition to having an antique gun collection,
普多斯基先生因为投资了被害人的基金
Mr. Podofski here lost more than 4 million bucks
赔了四百万美元
in our vic's lower tide fund.
他在基金赔钱的当天
He also left this message for Goldstein
给古德斯坦留了语音信息
the day the fund flatlined.
古德斯坦  在古时候
They had a way of handling folks like you
人们有专门的方法对付你这种人
in the old country, Goldstein.
那就是行刑队
It's called a firing squad.
你觉得他会给他遮眼布和香烟吗
Do you think he offered him a blindfold and a cigarette?
在古时候  人们有专门的方法
They had a way of handling folks like you
对付你这种人  古德斯坦
in the old country, Goldstein.
那就是行刑队
It's called a firing squad.
我觉得你们该弄清楚来龙去脉
I think some context is in order.
我只不过损失了四百万美元
I had only just lost $4 million.
没错  来龙去脉就是
Yes, and in that context,
你威胁要杀了古德斯坦
you threatened to kill Mr. Goldstein,
然后他果然就死了
and then he was killed.
昨晚11点到1点之间你在哪儿
Where were you last night between 11:00 and 1:00?
-在家睡觉  -有人能证明吗
- Asleep in my bed.  - And can anyone vouch for that?
-我  -要不要再加上我和我自己啊
- Me.  - Myself and I got your back, too?
好吧  这是有无法让人信服
Okay, look, I know how this appears.
但  我能解释
But I think there's, uh, an explanation.
说来听听
Fire away.
几个月前  我去伯曼罗斯做咨询
Several months ago, I had a consultation at Berman Rose.
当我提到枪时  古德斯坦问我怎样能
When I mentioned my guns, Goldstein asked if I knew
搞到一把福尔摩斯那样的枪
how he could get ahold of a Sherlock Holmes gun.
你是在指证阿瑟·柯南·道尔先生吗
So you're pointing the finger at sir Arthur Conan Doyle?
我是说古德斯坦对古董枪
I'm saying that Goldstein clearly had an interest
有很浓厚的兴趣
in antique guns.
可能是好奇害死猫
Maybe that interest got him killed.
既然你这么确信
You are so confident that
古德斯坦和别的人有过节
Goldstein got mixed up with someone else.
那么你应该不会介意
I'm sure you won't mind
把你的收藏品拿来给我们做检测吧
submitting your collection for testing with ballistics.
那可是古董啊  警探
These are antiques, detective.
你想因谋杀罪而被捕吗
Would you prefer being arrested for murder?
已经在对普多斯基的枪做弹道检测了
Ballistics has taken possession of Podofski's guns.
明天应该就能拿到初步结果
They should have preliminary results by tomorrow.
没人喜欢摊上谋杀的罪名啊
They never prefer to be arrested for murder.
-好  继续追查  -好的
- All right.  - Keep at it. Yeah.
哟  刚从交通执法部门
Yo. Just got a hit from Goldstein's car
弄到一张古德斯坦的罚单
from traffic enforcement.
昨晚开的违规停车罚单
Parking ticket from last night.
-不可能  -怎么了
- No way.  - What?
这绝对不可能
This has gotta be a joke.
你说什么呢  卡塞尔
What are you talking about, Castle?
古德斯坦开的是德罗林
Goldstein drives a Delorean.
就是《回到未来》里
The car used as a time machine
可以当作时光机器的那辆车
in "Back to the future"?
不可能  肯定是巧合
There's no way. That's a coincidence.
罚单是凌晨2点开的
The ticket was written at 2:00 in the morning.
即遇害之后  那车应该还在那儿
That's postmortem. Car should still be there.
没错  在东82区  列克星敦和第三大道之间
Yeah, east 82nd between Lex and third.
离公园只有几个街区
That's a few blocks from the park.
对  但既然要非法停车
Yeah, but if you're gonna park illegally,
为什么不停近一点呢
why not park closer?
因为  他要到那一街区的某个地方去
Because he was going somewhere on that block.
过去几个月内还有三张停车罚单
Three more parking tickets in the last several months,
都是在同一个区域
all on 82nd between Lex and third.
也就是说他定期去拜访那个地方
So he was going somewhere regularly on that block.
可能他女朋友在那儿
Maybe a girlfriend.
你觉得时间涟漪有可能在那儿吗
Unless you think that's where that time ripple is.
有可能
Could be.
继续调查  把那车弄走
Look into it. Pick that car up.
明白
Got you.
不是吧
You gotta be kidding me.
没错  这就是古德斯坦的车
Well, it's definitely Goldstein's car...
或者是  时间机器
Or a... Time machine.
是啊  若我没看错的话
Yep. If I'm not mistaken,
那儿有个通量电容器
that's a flux capacitor in there.
这儿还有个反应堆堆芯
And that is the reactor core.
也许卡塞尔是对的
Maybe Castle was right.
古德斯坦穿越到了现代
Goldstein came back to the future,
结果有来无回了
and he got whacked, huh?
-他为什么要来这儿呢  -不知道
- Why'd he keep coming here?  - I don't know.
可能车里会有些线索
Maybe there's something in the car that'll help.
希望如此吧  还有的忙呢
Hope so. Lot of doors to knock on.
哟  帕蒂  这儿有辆死者的车
Yo, Patty. I got a vic's car
来拖走吧
that needs towing.
在东82街的238号
It's at 238 east 82nd.
是一辆81或82年的德罗林
It's an '81 to '82 Delorean.
车牌号为纽约JLD
New York plates j-l-d--
过来一下  哈维
Hey, Javi.
我再打给你
Let me call you back.
先生  打扰一下
Excuse us, sir.
我是莱恩警探  这位是埃斯波西托警探
I'm detective Ryan. This is detective Esposito.
我们能问您几个问题吗
Do you mind if we ask you a few questions?
啊  警察先生  早上愉快
Ah! Top of the morning to you, constables.
亨利勋爵愿意为您服务
Lord Henry at your service.
谢谢  您能告诉我们
Uh, thanks. You mind telling us
这衣服哪儿来的吗
where you got those clothes?
哦  没问题  孩子  是我在公园对面的
Oh, not at all, dear boy. I picked them up
服饰用品店附近捡的
at the haberdashery across the park.
先生们  问完了的话
Well, gentlemen, if that is all,
那么日安啦
I shall bid you good day.
再等一下  老兄
Just a second, pal.
是这样的  我们认为这衣服
You know, we think those clothes
-可能和某个  -我说了日安
- might have been involved--  - I said "Good day."
-先生  我们想请您跟我们  -日安
- Sir, we need you to come down--  - Good day!
你没事吧  兄弟
You all right, bro?
没事
I'm fine.
放开我  你这恶棍
Unhand me, you rogue!
好  谢谢  莱恩
All right. Thank you, Ryan.
埃斯波西托怎么样
How's Esposito?
在家休息
At home resting.
那个亨利勋爵的话得到了证实
So our lord Henry's story checks out.
莱恩在亨利说的那个地方的垃圾桶里
Ryan found a matching ascot in a garbage can
找到了一条和衣服相匹配的领带
where henry said that he found the clothes.
那家伙是有点可疑  但他不是凶手
Our guy might be unstable, but he is not our killer.
古德斯坦为什么要穿成这样呢
So why was Goldstein wearing this costume?
这可是维多利亚时代的啊  样式很老了
Well, it's Victorian, antique...
完全符合时光穿越之说
Kind of fits with the whole time traveler theory,
不是吗
don't you think?
我真是搞不懂了  事情越来越复杂了
I don't know what to think, but the plot thickens.
衣服检测结果出来啦
Forensics came back on the clothes?
遭受了垃圾箱和流浪汉两轮劫难后
Between the garbage can and our homeless guy,
衣服上粘了很多恶心的东西
there was quite a list of gross-out substances,
那些我就不细说了  不过在
of which I will spare you the details, but I did find
右手套和衬衣袖口处
something interesting on the right hand glove
我发现了一些有趣的东西
and the right sleeve of the shirt--
-钾  硝酸盐和硫  -弹药残留物
- Potassium, nitrate and sulfur.  - Gunshot residue?
古德斯坦并不是空手去的
So Goldstein did not go quietly into the night,
-他拿着枪  -而且还击了
- He had a gun.  - And he fired back.
这里有发现
I got something here.
又一颗老式子弹
Another antique.
-和古德斯坦身上的那颗很像  -确实
- Looks exactly like the one that killed Goldstein. - It does.
假设凶手
Let's say that our killer...
假设凶手站在
Let's say that our killer is standing...
这里
Over here.
而古德斯坦是在那里被杀害的
Goldstein was killed all the way over there.
他们中间是一片平地
A nice flat area between them.
你在说什么  卡塞尔  某种游戏吗
What are you getting at, Castle, some kind of game?
不是游戏
Not a game.
古德斯坦穿着很正式的衣服
Goldstein was wearing formal turn-of-the-century clothes.
他用的是老式子弹
He shot an antique bullet
和杀他的那颗一样
identical to the one he was killed with,
说不定来自同一把枪
Probably fired from an identical gun.
4  5  6  7
Four, five, six, seven.
蕾妮说他大概是在午夜被杀害的
Lanie said he was killed at about midnight?
圣·詹姆斯教堂在那边
St. James church is right over there--
谢谢  在麦迪逊大街上
Thanks--on madison.
我猜他们从这儿可以清楚的听到
I bet they could hear the bells chiming
教堂的乐钟
all the way from over here.
39  40
39, 40...
他们相聚大概40步
They stood at about 40 paces from one another.
这不是游戏是什么
It wasn't a game.
是种古老的决斗游戏
It was an old-fashioned duel.
竟敢诽谤
Who dares besmirch...
-哦  别开枪  -我可真荣幸
- Oh, God, don't shoot!  - My honor?
别紧张  阿什利  他不会开枪的
It's okay, Ashley. He's not gonna shoot you.
你干什么呢  老爸
What the heck, dad?!
我还想问你这个问题呢
I might be asking you the same...
阿什利  这就是阿什利
Ashley? This is Ashley?
阿什  这是我爸爸  里克
Ash, this is my dad, Rick.
你拿着把枪干嘛
And I have no idea why he's waving a gun.
很高兴见到你卡塞尔先生
So nice to meet you, Mr. Castle.
我也是  阿什利
You, too, Ashley,
同时我也完全可以解释
And I have a perfectly good reason
为啥我拿着枪
why I'm waving a gun.
不好意思
Excuse us.
好好儿解释一下
Explain yourself.
我拿这把枪是为了查个案子
I got this gun for research for a case,
如果你今天和我联系过
which you might know if you had
这事儿就不难知道
checked in with me today.
这话什么意思
What's that supposed to mean?
就是说  我什么都会向你坦白
Let's just say, one of us has nothing to hide.
也许你才该解释一下这是什么情况
Perhaps you'd like to explain yourself?
解释什么  我和男生接吻吗
What, that I was kissing a boy?
-这很重要吗  -你说呢
- Is that a problem?  - You tell me.
爸爸  今晚我请阿什利过来
Dad, the only reason I invited Ashley over tonight
是想让你见见他
was so you could meet him.
好吧  让我见阿什利
Yes, well, me meeting Ashley
竟然把你的唇彩都弄到脸上去了
has smeared the lip gloss all over your face.
我  我应该告辞了
Uh, I-I-I really should be going.
可以再坐会儿  阿什利
You can stay, Ashley.
哦  关于枪
Oh, the gun.
是我的不对
My bad.
阿什利  请你千万要留下
Please, Ashley, stay.
-你可以试试这枪  -不用了  谢谢
- You can check out the gun.  - No, thanks.
一会儿给我电话
Call me later?
好的  若你的枪同意的话
Yeah, if it's okay with your gun...
你爸爸同意
Dad.
没事  我没关系的
Yeah, it's okay with me.
谢谢
Thank you.
我只是想告诉你
And I-I-I just want you to know
我很尊敬阿丽克西斯
how much I respect Alexis.
所以你不用担心
I mean, you don't have to
我会不尊敬她
worry about issues of respect.
她是我认识的最值得尊敬的人了
She's probably the most respectable person I know,
我也很尊敬你
and I-I respect you, too.
听你这样说我很高兴
That's good to know that.
不送了
Thank you.
我喜欢他
I like him.
小伙子挺尊老爱幼的
He's respectful.
知道了  谢谢
Got it. Thanks.
嘿
Hey.
嘿  经过弹道检查  伊万·普多斯基的枪
Hey. So Ivan Podofski's antique gun collection
都没问题
all cleared ballistics.
好吧  至少检查人员拿着古董枪
Well, at least some guy in ballistics
过了把瘾
had fun firing 'em off.
我也查了古德斯坦的妹妹和工作伙伴
I also checked with Goldstein's sister and coworkers.
他们都不知道
None of them know anything about
决斗和衣服的事
duels or Victorian clothes
也不知道他在东82街干什么
or what goldstein was doing on east 82nd.
听起来他有不可告人的秘密
Sounds like he had a secret life.
导致他参加决斗
That somehow led to a duel.
或者他发现某人玷污了他的荣誉
Maybe he figured someone besmirched his honor.
也有可能是为了女人  事实上
Maybe it was about a girl. Matter of fact, Alexis,
阿丽克西斯那个起了女人名字的新男友
Her new boyfriend--who has a girl's name, by the way--
昨晚以为我会对他开枪
He thought I was gonna shoot him last night.
-嘿  -嘿  埃斯波西托怎么样了
- Hey. - Hey. How's esposito?
他睡了  主要是因为他不睡也干不了啥事
He's sleeping in, mostly because he can't move.
你弄清古德斯坦在东82街干什么了吗
Did you figure out what Goldstein was doing on east 82nd?
不  但我搜查了古德斯坦的车子
No, but get this. I'm going through Goldstein's car,
找到了一叠收据  他肯定是准备
And I find a pile of receipts he must have been planning
拿去报销
To submit for reimbursement,
有一张是在三周前的咖啡馆
One of 'em from three weeks ago at a cafe.
这里  他写下了与特洛伊·肯沃西喝咖啡
On it, he wrote "Coffee with Troy Kenworth,"
那名字令我想起了某件事
And that name kinda rings a bell.
其中一个愤怒的低潮基金投资者
One of the angry lower tide fund investors?
不  但他的父亲查尔斯·肯沃西是
No, but his father Charles Kenworth was.
那家伙输了两百万
Guy loses 2 million bucks,
失去了他的房子  他的婚姻
And then he loses his house, his marriage,
然后在两个月前自杀了
And then two months ago, he killed himself.
特洛伊有任何前科吗
Did Troy have any priors?
是的  但都是之后的事
Yeah, more like afters.
他的父亲自杀之后
After his father committed suicide,
他被控分别在四间酒吧进行殴斗
He was charged with assault in four separate bar fights.
复仇  书里记载最古老的杀人动机
Revenge... Oldest motive for murder in the book.
或者特洛伊觉得
Maybe Troy thought someone
某人玷污了他父亲的荣誉
besmirched his father's honor.
然后他逼古德斯坦负上责任
And then he forced Goldstein to settle the score.
没错  是我发现他的尸体
Yeah, I was the one who found his body.
报告说他有一把猎枪
the report says that he used a shotgun.
嘿
Hey.
你为什么不进去
Why aren't you in there?
贝克特正在母爱泛滥
Beckett's doing a mothering thing.
想要减少房间里的男性荷尔蒙
Wanted to limit the testosterone on the room.
我无法想象你遭受的痛苦
I can't imagine walking in on that.
是的
Yeah.
太糟了  我尽量不去想起
Pretty messy. I try not to think about it.
我明白
I understand.
但自从那之后  肯沃西先生
But since then, mr. Kenworth,
你被四起待审的袭击案件指控
You have charges pending in four assault cases.
我喝多了  打架而已
I started drinking too much, lashed out.
但那些只是普通群众
But those were just random people at bars.
我是说  他们跟你父亲的死
I mean, they weren't even responsible
一点关系也没有
For your father's suicide.
但古德斯坦
But Goldstein...
他说服你父亲投资基金
He put your father in the fund
结果输光了他所有的财产
That lost him all of his money.
我能理解你责怪他
I could understand blaming him.
我有  但后来我跟他谈过了  他说
I did, but then I talked to him, and he said
他警告过我父亲要分拆资金
That he warned pop to diversify.
事实是  我父亲和母亲
And the fact is, dad and mom
多年前就一直有矛盾
Have been having problems for years.
当他输掉了房子后
When we lost the house,
而我又必须退学
and I had to drop out of school,
她承受不起  于是我母亲离开了他
It was the last straw, and mom left him.
这事把他逼上了绝路
That's what pushed him over the edge,
自从他死了之后  我妈努力挣钱
And ever since his death, mom's been struggling
支付我们的租金
To make payments on our apartment.
这就是你三周前
Is that why you went to go
见古德斯坦的理由吗
see Goldstein three weeks ago?
我想知道户口还有没有剩余的钱
I wanted to find out if any money was
那古德斯坦说什么了
left in the account. And what did Goldstein tell you?
事实  所有钱都输光了
The truth. All the money's gone.
那么你肯定很生气吧
Well, that must have made you pretty angry.
好吧  我知道你想说什么
Okay, I know what you're getting at,
但这次谈话改变了我
But that meeting is what turned me around.
自从那时候起我没喝过酒
I haven't had a drink since,
我母亲和我得以继续住在那里
Mom and I have been able to stay in our place.
我下学期甚至可以回学校读书
I might even go back to school next semester.
这全因为丹尼是一个正直的人
All because Danny's a stand-up guy,
他给我找了一份工作
and he gave me a job.
他遇害那晚上我在上班
That's where I was the night he got killed.
-在伯曼罗斯吗  -呃  不
- At Berman Rose?  - Uh, no.
-他给你找了什么工作  -我不能说
- What kind of a job did danny give you? - I can't say.
我签了保密协议
Look, I had to sign a confidentiality agreement. Okay?
-我会被开除的  -或者你会被逮捕
- I could be fired. - Or you could be arrested.
这工作是在列克星敦和第三区之间的八十二大街吗
Is this job on 82nd between Lex and third?
福格先生赌了多少英镑
What was the exact number of pounds that mr. Fogg bet
说他能在八十天内环游世界
That he could travel around the world in 80 days?
-两万  -回答正确  先生
- 20,000. -Correct, sir.
通向地心的火山叫什么名字
Name the volcano that led to the center of the earth.
哦  我想是
Oh, I want to say--
纽约警局  开门
Nypd. Open the dn door.
-我们在哪里  -维多利亚时期的伦敦
- Where are we? - Victorian london.
-什么时候  -一九八二年
-When are we? - 1892.
这到底是什么地方
What is this place?
煤气灯联盟  一个地下19世纪科幻小说社团
The gaslamp league, a private steampunk society.
向前直走
Straight ahead
你会找到我们的俱乐部主席  欧文·皮特森
You'll find our club president, Owen Peterson.
他在老式脚踏车上
He's on the penny-farthing.
那好吧
All right then.
噢  是《回到过去》里的时间机器
Oh, it's the time machine from "Time and away".
-我喜欢那部电影  -欧文
- I love that movie. - Owen!
来首诗吧
Give us a poem!
科幻小说
Steampunk.
是一个包含了
it's a subculture that embraces
过去的单纯和浪漫的亚文化
The simplicity and romance of the past
同时  结合希望与承诺
At the same time, couples it with the hope and promise
还有未来主义设计的纯粹
And sheer super-coolness of futuristic design.
你说你是克隆人  还有更多的你吗
You're cloned, you say? There are more of you?
人越多越好玩
Well, the more the merrier!
对你们这些羔羊来说  我是真实的
To ewes all, I'll be true.
打搅一下  皮特森先生
Excuse me, mr. Peterson.
-我是探长  -我能试试那个吗
- I'm detective-- - can I try that?
我不知道说什么  探长
I don't know what to tell you, detective.
我们昨天听说了丹尼的事  难以置信
We all heard about Danny yesterday. Hard to believe.
那晚早些时候他来过这里
We saw him here the night before
你跟你的朋友放声大笑
Well, the way you and your friends were yukking it up
令我感觉你们并不伤心
Makes me feel like you weren't so upset.
我们只是比较浪漫派  探长
We're just romantics, detective.
对现今社会不满意
Look at the world, don't like what we see,
所以来这里再创造一个
So we recreate it here--
一块可以无限发挥人类潜力和创造力的绿洲
An oasis where human potential and ingenuity is limitless,
一个甚至连死亡都充满诗意
Where there's poetry and wonder and
奇迹和价值的地方
meaning, even in death.
-他那晚几点离开的  -十一点半左右
- What time did he leave that night? - Around 11:30.
-他有说他要去干什么吗  -没有
- Did he tell you what he was doing? - No.
他去公园决斗了
He went to the park for a duel.
什么意思  决斗
What do you mean, a duel?
人们向对方开枪的那种
The kind where people shoot at each other.
他们用的是古董枪
They were using antique guns.
你有任何头绪吗
Do you know anything about that?
决斗用手枪
Dueling pistols.
还有  呃  氧化铅外壳的子弹
With, uh, lead balls with white coating?
最近开过枪
This has been fired recently.
但那是为了表演用的
But they're just for show.
亚当  停下  停下
Adam, stop! Stop!
-噢  我的天  -噢噢  天啊
- Oh, my god! - Oh! Oh, goodness!
快让开  快让开
Out of the way! Get out of the way!
我想他要去时间机器那里了
I think he's going for the time machine!
只是一些问讯工作
It's just a bunch of interviews.
我不晓得你为什么不请假算了
I don't know why you didn't take the whole day off.
因为我没事
Because I'm fine.
墨菲
Murphy!
把他拦下
Stop him!
嘿  埃斯波西托
Hey, esposito.
你的脖子怎么样
How's your neck?
没错  我开枪了
Yeah, I shot him.
他就只是那样向后倒下了
He just kinda crumpled over backwards,
我以为他在开玩笑
But I thought he was kidding.
我跑过去以为他随时会跳起来
I jogged over expecting him to jump up any second,
但他只是  躺在那里
But he was just-- just lying there so still,
然后我看见了血  听到茱莉亚尖叫
A-and then I saw the blood, and I hear Julia.
她跪在地上尖叫  不  上帝  不
She's on her knees screaming, "No. Please, god, no."
我  我吓坏了
I-I-I freaked out.
我们拿了他的衣服  然后  然后逃跑了
We took his clothes, and--and I just ran.
茱莉亚  你是说古德斯坦的助理
Julia? You mean Goldstein's assistant?
他爱上了她
He was in love with her.
他们好上很久了吗
Had they been seeing each other a long time?
不  不  丹只亲过她一次
No, no, Dan just kissed her once,
几周前在酒吧外面
A couple weeks ago out at a bar,
但她  她对他没有兴趣
But she--she wasn't interested in him.
所以你跟她好上了
So you were involved with her?
也不算是
Not really involved,
但丹上周晚上抓到我们
But Dan caught us fooling around in my office
在我办公室里鬼混
Late one night last week.
除了决斗以外
And you couldn't think of a better way of
你们就想不到其他更好的方法了吗
settling this other than a duel?
我们只是觉得那会很有趣
We--we--we just thought it would be funny.
丹尼发誓没人会受伤
Danny swore that we couldn't get hurt.
向对方开枪
Shooting at each other?
他计算过那些复杂的公式
He--he ran all these complex equations.
他说我们隔着四十步的距离
He said--said that at 40 paces, there was no chance
是不可能伤害到对方的
That we could actually hit each other, something about
什么十八世纪的枪  枪管里没有装膛线
18th century guns having no rifling in the barrel.
那如果你们不能伤害对方的话
So if you couldn't kill each other,
决斗还有什么意义
What was the point of the duel?
讨茱莉亚的欢心
to impress Julia.
她从来不会对我们这样的怪胎认真的
she would never get serious with geeks like us.
但我们觉得  如果她看见我们为她决斗
But we figured that maybe if-- if she saw us duel over her,
那  或许我们  我们其中
Then... maybe that one--that one of--
我们其中一个可以
One of us c--
茱莉亚证实了她是
Julia confirmed that she was
决斗时唯一的目击者
The only other person present at the duel.
没其他人知道
No one else knew.
好的  让她走
All right. Let her go.
你怎么可以把枪口对着某人
how do you point the gun at someone
开枪  却没想过会杀死他
And shoot and not expect to kill them?
他们被那些浪漫蒙蔽了双眼
Well, they were blinded by the romance of it all,
而且古德斯坦计算过了
And Goldstein did the math.
决斗的事还有低潮基金
Well, between this and the lower tide fund,
或者他并不是天才
Maybe he wasn't such a genius.
又或者只是运气差
Or maybe he's just unlucky.
那我就遇上难题了
Well, then I've got a problem,
因为我要给检察官一份报告
Because I have to make a recommendation to the D.A.
谋杀和误杀分别
Between murder and manslaughter,
被判的刑期可是终身监禁
The difference being life in prison
或者几年
Or just a couple of years.
我是说  古董枪真的那么不准吗
I mean, are antique guns really so inaccurate?
只有一个方法可以知道
Only one way to find out.
那是你的靶子  这是我的
That's your target. That's my target.
是的  我
Yeah, well, I--
打你自己的靶子
Shoot your target.
绝对是误杀
Manslaughter it is.
没错
Yeah.
爸
Hey, dad.
我的宝贝女儿
Hey, there's my girl.
过来
Come here.
对不起  稍等
Sorry. Hang on.
好了  搞掂了
Okay. There we go.
昨天晚上
Hey, about, uh, last night,
我  有点事出突然
Um, I was... It was unexpected.
对不起
Yeah. I'm -- I'm sorry.
我也很抱歉
I'm sorry, too.
我应该告诉你阿什利是男生的
I should've told you Ashley was a boy.
不  为什么要破坏掉这个惊喜呢
No, why, uh, why spoil the surprise?
我有个问题想问你
So I have a question for you,
但是有点尴尬
but it's a little embarrassing.
-我最喜欢你尴尬的样子了  -爸
- Ooh. I love when you embarrass yourself.  - Dad.
听着  你可以
Well, hey, listen, you can, uh...
你可以问我任何事情
You can ask me whatever you want,
而且  我保证  我会尽力
and... I promise, I'll do my best
缓解所有的尴尬
to make it as unembarrassing as possible.
你怎么知道自己是不是恋爱了呢
How do you know when you're in love?
我知道这是一种情绪
I know it's an emotion...
一种你无法确切描述的感觉
a feeling, and you can't exactly define,
只有你亲身经历才知道感觉对了
like, technically, how you know when you're feeling it,
但是因为我以前从来没有过这种感觉
but since I've never felt it before,
我怎么知道我现在感觉到的是不是爱情呢
how do I know what I'm feeling is even it at all?
当然  除了我现在
Except, of course, for the fact
体会到了这些前所未有过的感觉
that I'm feeling all these things I've never felt before,
我的胃  我的喉咙
like in my stomach and my throat
好像就连我的耳朵都感觉到了
and even kind of in my ears.
这些只能说明这就是爱  对吧
I mean, which just has to mean that it's love, right?
特别是我只有在跟阿什利在一起
Considering I only feel them when I'm with Ashley
或是想到他的时候  才有这些感觉
or thinking about him,
这只能说明我恋爱了  对吧
I mean, that's gotta be love, right?
-如果  -因为以前
- If --  - 'Cause I'm feeling all these things
我在诗歌里读到过
I've read about in poems
还有在歌曲里听到过
and heard about in songs
但却不全然理解的东西
but never completely understood,
我现在全理解了  我能体会了
but now I do. I understand. And I'm listening
我现在对这些音乐和诗歌
to all this music and reading all this poetry
有了一个全新的喜人的理解了
in a completely new and glorious light,
这只能说明我恋爱了
which I think just has to mean that it's love.
-你觉得呢  -我
- What do you think?  - I --
我无法不想他  爸
I can't stop thinking about him, daddy.
我也乐意时刻惦记着他
I don't even want to,
因为他是最好  最体贴  最可爱的人
'cause he's the greatest, sweetest, most adorable guy,
他笑得时候鼻子会皱起来
and his nose crinkles when he laughs,
然后我也就跟着开心
and I'm just so happy.
谢谢老爸  我爱你
Thanks, dad. I love you.
我现在觉得舒服多了
I feel so much better now.
跟你聊天很高兴
I'm glad we had that talk.
你怎么知道自己是否恋爱了
How do you know when you're in love?
所有歌都听得懂了
All the songs make sense.
亚当 墨菲没杀古德斯坦
Adam Murphy didn't kill Goldstein.
但是他认罪了
But he confessed.
我认为他也相信是自己干的
And I believe that he believes he did it,
但其实不是
but he didn't.
-说来听听  -我一直在想
- Do tell.  - It bothered me
我们在射击场怎么也打不中靶子的事
that we couldn't hit the target at the shooting range,
所以我就对那两把枪做了弹道测试
and so I ran ballistics on the dueling pistols.
射中丹尼尔·古德斯坦的子弹
The bullet that hit Daniel Goldstein
不符合任何一把枪的弹道测试结果
didn't match either one of them.
亚当不可能是凶手
Adam couldn't have killed him.
你是在说公园里的阴谋论
You're talking full-on, grassy knoll conspiracy theory.
不是理论  是事实
Not theory, fact.
当时有第三个枪手在场
There was a third shooter,
他才是我们要找的凶手
and that's our killer.
贝克特
Hey, Beckett!
找到亚当 墨菲的子弹了吗
Did you find Adam Murphy's bullet?
那个铅球
Lead ball.
找到了  他没打中古德斯坦
Yep. He didn't kill Goldstein.
却打中了松鼠
But he did kill squirrelstein.
够巧的吧
What are the odds, huh?
不  它也被扒光了
Oh, no. They took his clothes, too.
你把它拿回去吧
- Could you?  - Aww.
我明白  不好意思
Yeah, I know. I'm sorry.
那么我们知道
Okay, so we know that
古德斯坦当晚站在这
Goldstein was standing right over here...
面对着站在那边的亚当
facing Adam, who was right over there.
没错  那么如果我们的凶手想要杀他
Right, and if our killer wanted to shoot him
却又不能被这两个人看见
without either of them seeing him,
他就只能站在
he would be standing right over...
那  那个树丛边
there, by that clump of trees.
探员  我发现了衣物纤维
Detective, I've got clothing fibers.
这根线看上去眼熟吧
This thread looks familiar?
我无论到哪都能认出这种红色天鹅绒
Oh, I'd recognize that burgundy velvet anywhere.
让人想起了19世纪科幻小说  不是吗
Kinda says "steampunk", doesn't it?
实际上
Matter of fact,
我想我知道凶器是什么了
I think I know the murder weapon.
《地心历险记》里的火山
Volcano in "Journey to the center of the earth"--
是斯奈山吗
Snaefells?
卡塞尔
Castle.
离不开这里是吧  有什么可以帮忙的吗
Couldn't stay away, huh? Can I get you guys something?
当然  特洛伊
Sure, Troy.
我们在找一个枪手
We're looking for a shooter.
事实上  我想我们已经找到了
Actually, I think we already found one.
顺便说一句  制服不错
Nice uniform, by the way.
我们找到了你父亲的猎枪
We found your father's shotgun.
我们知道你为了打老式的铅弹
We know that you modified it
而改过那把枪
in order to shoot antique lead ball bullets.
你们在说什么
What are you talking about?
亚当 墨菲已经认罪了对吧
Adam Murphy already confesse right?
结果发现不可能是亚当 墨菲干的
Turns out Adam Murphy couldn't have done it.
是那种科学弹道之类的东西证明的
It's a sciencey ballistics thing.
在亚当和古德斯坦开枪的那一瞬间
It was pretty clever, firing your father's shotgun
扣动你父亲的枪
at the exact moment that
真是很聪明的做法
Adam and Goldstein fired their guns.
使亚当相信
Making Adam believe
是他杀了古德斯坦的
that he was the one that killed Goldstein,
就在教堂敲响午夜钟声的时候
right as the church bells chimed midnight.
难道不是吗
Isn't that right?
每天晚上看着他在这里
Seeing him in here every night
穿着那荒唐的衣服
in that ridiculous outfit...
然后大把大把地扔钱
just throwing around all that money?
为什么他可以那样活着
Why should he get to live like that
而我父亲却死了
when my dad's dead?
得知凶手是俱乐部的工作人员
Knowing that our shooter was a staff member at the club
我们马上就想到了特洛伊
led us straight back at Troy.
他无意中听到亚当和古德斯坦在计划决斗
He overheard Adam and Goldstein planning the duel
于是就抓住了这个机会
and took his opportunity.
我们去询问其他工作人员的时候
And then Troy's alibi fell apart
推翻了特洛伊的不在场证明
as soon as we started interviewing other staff members
在决斗前后的半个小时里
who couldn't remember seeing him there
没有人曾在俱乐部里看到过他
half an hour before or after the duel.
为了个姑娘决斗  为死去的亲人报仇
Dueling over a girl, avenging the death of a loved one...
-还真是浪漫的入骨  -也很悲剧
- Cuts to the heart of romance.  - And the tragedy.
说到悲剧
Speaking of tragedy,
你们听说埃斯波西托探员的事了吗
did you hear about detective Esposito?
没有  他怎么了
No. What about him?
他
Oh. He...
天啊  不是吧
God, no.
伙计  你怎么搞的
Dude... What happened?
-不  我不想听  -埃斯波西托
- No, no, I don't want to hear it.  - Esposito...
-伙计  你没事吧  -我没事
- Dude, are you okay?  - No, I'm okay. Whoa!
我真的没事  兄弟
No, I r -- I really am fine, bro.
这个是从储藏室拿的
We got this stuff from storage.
你们真应该看看自己的表情
Oh, you shoulda seen your faces.
-头  你还真厉害  -说到悲剧
- Captain, you really sold that.  - Speaking of tragedy,
你们听说埃斯波西托探员的事了吗
did you hear about detective Esposito?"
头
- Hey.  - Sir.
-装的真像  -我还没全好
- That was good. - Ow! I'm not really that fine.
-对了  我来  -抱歉
- Oh, oh, yeah, let me just--  - Sorry.
颈托  颈托
Neck brace, please. Neck brace.
-扣紧点  扣紧点  -好的  好的
- Lock it down. Lock it down.  - Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
-凯特  -乔什你怎么来了
- Kate.  - Josh, what are you doing here?
我收到你的短信了
Oh, I got your text.
我说我去接你的那条短信吗
You mean the text where I said I was gonna pick you up?
没错  可我就在附近
Yeah, I was nearby.
乔什  这位是蒙哥马利警长
Well, uh, Josh, this is captain Montgomery,
理查德·卡塞尔
Richard castle,
还有埃斯波西托和莱恩探员
detectives Esposito and Ryan.
-小伙子们  -小伙子
- Hey, boys.  - Boys?
-今天抓坏人了吗  -每天都抓
- Catch any bad guys today?  - Every day.
你搞掂了吗
You all set?
是的  让我拿上东西
Yeah, let me just get my stuff.
好的
Okay.
那么
So...
你和贝克特
You and Beckett?
我们怎么了
Mm-hmm. What about us?
我问你呢啊
You tell me.
你就是那个作家
You're the writer.
没错
Yeah.
没错  那么
Yeah, and...
那么你是
And you are?
凯特没跟你提过我  对吧
Oh, Kate hasn't told you about me, has she?
有什么好提的呢
What's to tell?
可以走了吗
You ready to go?
当然  回头见
Yeah. Hey, I'll see you around.
再见  伙计们
Bye, guys.
回见
Later.
你一个人吗
Just you?
是的
Yes.
谢谢你昨晚陪我聊天
Thanks for that talk last night.
我觉得舒服多了
I feel so much better.
你永远
Hey, you can, uh...
永远都可以跟我说
You can always talk to me...
或是冲着我说
Or at me.
恋爱太累人了
Being in love is exhausting.
是啊  你这点倒是没说错
Yeah, you got that right.
你没事吧  老爸
You okay, dad?
你好像心不在焉
You seem distracted.
谁说的
What are you talking about?
我对着你永远是百分之百集中精神的
You have my undivided attention.
很好  因为我今晚想要约会
Good, because I want to go on a date tonight.
怎么样
How's that sound?
当然  很好  玩得开心点
Of course. Great. Have a good time.
我是说跟你约会  爸
I meant with you, dad.
你永远都是我的依靠
You'll always be my go-to guy.
是奶奶教你这么做的吧
Did Gram put you up to this?
我不知道你在说什么
I have no idea what you're talking about.
你是同情我
Pity date.
那也无所谓
I'll take it.
你一点都不会撒谎
You're a terrible liar.